It's been a while since I went to CosStream.
I used to go when I was younger cause they're
one of the few events with industry booths.
Nagomi's here, too.
Doing another new character, I assume.
I haven't kept up so I'm out of the loop.
That being said...
I missed cosplay events so much!
Stop that!
I'm here to see my students today!
I'm working overtime as their advisor!
Cosplay Changing Rooms
Oh God!
I was on autopilot to the goddamn changing rooms!
Dressing Room: Nagomi
Is that everything?
You're good, Nagomi-san!
Thanks! She's cute!
Great craftsmanship, too.
The bust might be a bit tight,
so let me know if you need it adjusted.
Don't worry about that. I'm used to it.
You still thinking about that Liliel?
I've never seen you get this worked up
about a newbie before, Nagomi-san.
She does this all the time,
but I've got to get her to cool off.
She reminded me of Mayura.
When I saw her pic,
I could tell how much she loved the character.
Just like Mayura-sama, huh?
I always did the most popular characters so
I could be the biggest cosplayer out there.
I promoted the hell out of myself, too.
But no matter how hard I tried,
Mayura-sama and her Lustalotte
cosroms always outsold mine.
Then she freakin' retired on me...
W-wait, so that was you taking it out on her?
Don't make me out to be some bully!
She's definitely got skill, but she's wasting it.
She'll never get anywhere if she restricts
herself to a single character.
She'll end up screwing herself over someday.
Cosplay is art. Why limit yourself like that?
I love all cosplay, no matter where it's coming from.
I wish you'd act like it...
Or this'll end up screwing YOU over someday.
So that's why you said that?
To get her to try other things?
No, I said it 'cause I don't like her and
I wanted her to feel bad.
So I was right!
But if that's enough to make her upset,
she's not gonna last long, anyways.
You're Not Liliel!
Liliel-chan!
You've barely gotten started!
We were gonna head out.
You okay?
Y-yeah, go ahead!
Maybe... I don't love cosplay enough.
Milady Magino, over here!
W-where's Liliel?
Don't worry about her!
She's just taking extra time to put on her costume!
But...
If something's wrong,
it's up to you to make it right.
Okay!
We'd talked about this, but damn...
It really is a ghost town out here.
That kind of sucks,
but we might as well get started.
Yes, you're right.
Nagomi-san! Let's do it out here!
Here comes the Queen herself.
That's Miss Nagomi!
She definitely has a different vibe,
like this is just her everyday.
Is it confidence?
From her expression to her aura,
she looks exactly like Icola's art.
But Liliel looks just as good as she does!
Nagomi-san, no stopping!
Wait, I saw him! He was right there!
What? Saw who?
You guys gotta settle down and listen!
I think you're the one who needs to settle down.
I saw him out there! My Kai-sama!
Are her 2D delusions getting that bad?
I'm telling the truth!
Was it a daydream? A hallucination?
Is God rewarding me for all my hard work
by bringing my darling Kai-sama to life?
She really does live off in la-la land, doesn't she?
Can I be cringe for a second?
Uh, sure?
I caught feels!
It's time.
Huh?
It's time!
I'm going to put on my best cosplay performance ever!
Show me the Icola info sheet again!
Here!
I-I've never seen her this excited!
17 years old, lives alone in the country,
secretly the daughter of a powerful mage...
ICOLA
A 17-year-old girl who lives alone in the countryside.
Secretly the daughter of a powerful mage.
That's all the info we've got, besides her art...
I'll have to imagine her personality myself.
My portrayal of her might be the first
impression the public gets of her...
How does she smile? What scents surround her?
What's her hometown like?
Who is she?
Who am I?
Sorry, could I borrow Nagomi-san for a moment?
I don't think so. Not now...
She's already headed out.
Something's not right.
It's been an hour since the event started,
and barely anyone has come by.
Why hasn't anyone left the industry booth area?
What's going on?
I'll go check it out.
I'll come with you, seeing as no one's around.
Okay.
What is everyone doing outside?
What are they taking pictures of?
Some cool bird or something?
I-I can't believe this is happening!
Huh?
I-I know what they're doing!
All of these people...
...are taking pictures of Nagomi!
What?!
This kind of crowd at an event this
size is completely unheard of!
NAGOMI Photo Area
Come outside for photos of Nagomi-san!
Nagomi-san is over here!
The crowd must have been
too big for the industry space,
so they moved it outside...
This is what it means to be a top cosplayer!
I should have known!
Nagomi-san needs a ten-minute break!
Pardon us, everyone!
Nagomi-san, drink some water.
Don't drag me back to reality without warning me.
One more hour, and we'll go back to the booth.
Sure, but I still haven't spotted Kai-sama.
How do you know that?
He might be in the crowd some-
Are you stupid?
I can see the face of every photographer here.
Okay, let's keep going!
Seems like we'll just have to wait till
Nagomi-chan is done with her shoot.
We can't!
By then, all the attendees will have gone home!
He's so confident.
He knows she'll make it work,
despite our current situation.
Where is she, though?
She should be done by now.
Y-yeah... I'll give her a call.
Ririsa? Everything okay, Ririsa?
Did she forget something?
I've probably got a spare if she needs it!
I-it's worse than that.
I can't find my skirt!
What?
Ririsa!
Oh, no...
Y-you can't find your skirt?
Did you leave it at home?
N-no, I know I put it in my suitcase...
Could someone have grabbed it
when you weren't looking,
thinking it was theirs?
That would make things difficult.
There's no way we could ask every
cosplayer if they've seen it...
Maybe just the Liliel cosplayers?
No, let's ask Lost and Found first.
I'm gonna go check Lost and Found!
Someone might've turned it in there.
Wait.
Senpai, wait. It's... It's fine.
It's really fine.
I don't love cosplay enough.
I mean, who loses a big piece of their costume?
I don't deserve to wear my Liliel cosplay!
Oh, Ririsa-chan...
You're still thinking about what she said?
She was wrong!
Huh? Did something happen?
Nagomi-san said that?!
T-that sent her spiraling?
No, c'mon, it probably meant a lot to Ririsa...
Still, though!
Okay.
Okumura-kun.
Remember what I told you:
if you have something to say,
then say it.
Don't hold back.
R-Ririsa, don't just give up like this.
We made a promise! We're gonna do this, together!
I know, but-
But what?!
What about our club room?
No, I shouldn't bring that up.
It's my job to deal with our club room.
What do I need from her?
No, that's not it, either!
O-oh, right.
We need to write that report,
or we'll lose our room.
Who cares if we lose our room?
The room stopped being an issue the second
we decided not to use that other report.
How can you be cool with this?
You're doing this for yourself,
because you want to cosplay, right?
Yeah, but... Is that a good enough reason?
My only other reason is to show
everyone how much I love Liliel, but...
But I could do that by making a doujinshi,
or buying merch.
I don't need to cosplay.
You're overthinking things!
Why are you taking this so seriously?!
What's wrong with taking it this seriously?!
Okay, so why did you even bother cosplaying before?!
I don't know. I wish I did.
I have no idea.
Riri-
Magino-san?
Sorry, I should've mentioned one more thing.
Once you've said everything you want to say,
you need to know when to stop.
Don't say anything you don't truly mean.
Let it end there.
Thank you...
Hold on, Okumura-kun! Where are you going?!
You're just gonna leave her here?!
You two should go get your pictures.
But what about...
This is Ririsa's problem.
Okumura, milord, let's talk over here! Come!
Yes, let's go!
M-my student is in trouble... She needs her advisor!
Mayuri-sensei?
You've got such good fashion sense.
If you think this is good,
then I know you've got zero fashion sense.
I heard what's going on.
What's on your mind?
I've never seen Senpai that mad.
It's my fault. I made him angry.
I disappointed him.
It's all my fault!
I'm a horrible person!
You can't know how someone feels,
so don't make assumptions like that.
Though it's good that you're being considerate.
You're not mad at me, Sensei?
I made all those promises to you, but here I am...
Sure, but...
I'm your teacher.
And teachers don't get mad?
I mean, they do, but like...
Oh, here, let me tell you a story.
When I was in high school,
I didn't have any friends.
It was tough...
not being able to talk about the things I liked.
She was just like me.
But then...
Oh, this is the character you want to make?
Her outfit is so cute. Here's how I would do that...
My home ec teacher gave me the support I needed.
She never got annoyed with me.
Whatever I came to her with,
she'd say, "Great, go do it!"
Is that why you decided to become a home ec teacher?
...Huh?
Huh?
Wait... Is that why I went into teaching?
Did I forget? What's wrong with me?!
I told myself teaching was the most stable career option.
Guess I did follow my dreams after all.
You can't escape the things you love.
Makes sense.
It's why I'm so determined to help her.
I know what I can do for her.
Well, if you're not cosplaying,
then I don't need to be here.
I'm gonna go get some work done.
O-okay. Sorry, Sensei.
Listen! Mayuri-sensei is leaving, okay?!
She's not here!
This'll be on the test!
O-okay!
Now I've disappointed both of them...
"You can't know how someone feels,
so don't make assumptions like that."
Excuse me, has anyone brought in
a bag with part of a costume inside?
Excuse me, I have a question!
Yes?
I'm looking for a Liliel skirt.
Do you think you might have grabbed it?
We can't get changed without it!
Hold on, I'll check my bags!
I'll check mine, too!
I'll ask around.
Thank you so much!
This is Ririsa's problem, so...
So that means it's my problem, too!
I'm going to find her Liliel skirt!
Okumura-kun's such a sweet guy.
I'm a little jealous.
Milady Magino?!
I wish I knew what to do...
M... Mayura-sama?!
Thank God I was on autopilot and
brought my costume with me!
It's been three years, huh?
Oh my gosh, you remember me?!
Of course. I've been hoping to see you here.
I...
I started cosplaying!
I wanted to be a cosplayer just like you!
But now, I'm not sure if I have the
right reason to be cosplaying, so...
Maybe you could tell me!
What's the reason you cosplay?
Let me think...
It's complicated!
INTENSE
Can you be more specific?!
At first, I did it for myself.
I wanted to distance myself from the shy wallflower.
I wanted to be someone different.
But as I got into cosplay, I started doing it for Lustalotte.
She was my reason for a while.
And as I got more famous,
I sometimes felt I had a duty to cosplay at certain events.
Sometimes, I cosplayed just to cosplay.
Sometimes I did it for myself.
Right now, I'm cosplaying to help you.
Sensei?
You taught me an important lesson, you know:
The reason really doesn't matter.
I cosplay because I want to.
I just can't help myself.
How about you? Do you want to cosplay?
Of course I do! I just...
Then have faith.
You've got a partner who feels the same way, don't you?
My favorite is when the hero
comes rushing in to save her.
Ririsa!
We found it! We've got it!
Senpai!
I'm so sorry! I grabbed it when I was in a rush...
I'm really, really sorry!
It's okay. Thanks for helping us find it.
Here you go, Ririsa.
I'm sorry. I wasn't... I...
Ririsa.
Remember all the things you love?
You love Liliel, sexy costumes, and cosplay, too.
And you're sure that's good enough?
A real otaku NEVER judges
someone by the things they love!
And it doesn't matter how you show that love.
There's no one 'right' way.
Whatever you love, however you do it,
all that matters is that you love it!
And who cares if someone else doesn't believe that?!
Someone might talk shit about that, sure,
but that's not because of us.
Maybe they've got their own shit going on,
or something they're afraid to admit out loud.
But if that ever gets to you,
and you lose faith in yourself,
if your heart ever starts to break,
I'll be there for you! I'll be right there, rooting for you!
Your Liliel is...
No. You're not Liliel.
It's not because you're Liliel.
You're...
You are Ririsa Amano!
Ririsa, the cosplayer!
Ririsa, who's got this!
Ririsa, who's gonna cosplay Liliel!
R-right!
Okumura, milord!
You found her missing piece?!
Oh, thank God!
Sorry about the scare.
That's good, because Nagomi is
nearly done with her photo shoot!
In fifteen mintues,
all the attendees are gonna start heading out.
It takes me an hour to get into costume...
Yeah... And by then, everyone will be gone.
Twist my arm, why don't you?
Wait, Lady Mayura?!
And that's the cosplay you were going
to debut at last year's Winter Comiket!
Whaaa?! W-why are you here?!
Are you going to let your partner's
hard work go to waste?
But there's no time...
Then I suppose you need your advisor...
...to give the performance of a lifetime.
Mayura vs. Nagomi!!